<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christopher T. Ogden</title>
    <description>My personal blog</description>
    <link>http://ctogden.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ctogden.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Long term thinking</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been amazed by plans for a future that is almost certainly outside the lifespan of involved parties. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such as these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A thousand year endowment left to Hartwick College by an eccentric lawyer in the 1930s. This gift had the potential to disrupt the entire world economy with its vast vast accrual of compound interest.[^1]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pretty much any project of &lt;a href=&quot;http://longnow.org/&quot;&gt;The Long Now Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, but especially the ten thousand year clock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;99 year leases.[^2]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to think that this sort of thing was silly.  But then I remembered that philanthropy is about others, and improving a life a thousand years from now is just as meaningful as helping someone today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very least, it makes our constant worries about the daily grind of life seem a bit less significant, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[^1]: I first read about this in a post on &lt;a href=&quot;http://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2011/09/the-magic-of-compound-interest.html&quot;&gt;Marginal Revolution&lt;/a&gt;.  I think I remember reading elsewhere that the college challenged the terms in court and received the money early.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[^2]: My neighbor mentioned the other day that he had asked the county fair to move the ticket booth at the main entrance from a section of his yard by the main gate, as their 99 year lease was up. That was the impetus for this post, though probably the poorest example above; long term leases are often used to circumvent certain taxes.  In the case of my neighbor, perhaps there was a no transfer clause as well?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ctogden.com//2014/01/03/Long-term-thinking/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ctogden.com//2014/01/03/Long-term-thinking/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Practice Resurrection</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally got around to watching Skyfall[^1] last weekend.  In one scene, Bond is asked about his hobbies.  &amp;ldquo;Resurrection&amp;rdquo; is his reply.[^2]  It reminded me of a catchphrase I devised in the past: &amp;ldquo;Practice resurrection&amp;rdquo;.  It was catchy, but not knowing what it meant made it rather hard to use.  Now I&amp;rsquo;ve got a better idea.  It goes hand in hand with the goal of making mistakes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fall.  Get up.  Fall.  Get back up again.  &amp;ldquo;Practice resurrection.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[^1]: A thrilling, and also deeply disturbing film.  I&amp;rsquo;m referring to the scene in which Bond slips, uninvited, into the shower of an abused woman deeply in need of help, not sexual partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[^2]: In the opening scenes Bond is shot and falls a great distance from the roof of a train into waterfalls below.  Everyone believes him dead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ctogden.com//2013/04/24/Practice-Resurrection/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ctogden.com//2013/04/24/Practice-Resurrection/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It has been awhile</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly two months since my last post.  Oops.  That shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have happened&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which isn&amp;rsquo;t to say I haven&amp;rsquo;t been busy.  It was a rough semester.  19 credits.  7 challenging classes. I made it through it though, and lucky me, I&amp;rsquo;ve now got over 6 weeks off (about 4 remaining).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying the time off and the opportunity to read some books.  I got &lt;em&gt;Mr. Penumbra&amp;rsquo;s 24-Hour Bookstore&lt;/em&gt; for Christmas.  I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of Robin Sloan&amp;rsquo;s blogs and other schemes (I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://snarkmarket.com/&quot;&gt;Snarkmarket&lt;/a&gt; and his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.robinsloan.com/summer-reading/&quot;&gt;Summer Reading series&lt;/a&gt;).  The story was good, but not great.  That&amp;rsquo;s okay.  It&amp;rsquo;s a first novel, and it still left me with plenty of interesting thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon I&amp;rsquo;ll be finished with Frank Chimero&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Shape of Design&lt;/em&gt;.  I started it when I first got it, but it&amp;rsquo;s been awhile so I started fresh.  I want to take it slowly, savor it, but instead I find myself rushing ahead.  And then I&amp;rsquo;ll set it down to make sure I get the most I can out of it.  It&amp;rsquo;s not heavy reading, but it&amp;rsquo;s not light either, and that liminality is burdensome, especially when I had anticipated the book for so long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also started &lt;em&gt;Mockingjay&lt;/em&gt;, the third book in The Hunger Games trilogy, yesterday.  More than halfway through it already.  It&amp;rsquo;s good.  It&amp;rsquo;s written for children/teenagers, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing.  When dealing with the questions the book raises about the human condition, academic prose isn&amp;rsquo;t going to do any better at resolving those enquiries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll save other books for other days.  It&amp;rsquo;s better that I read them first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you about a project I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a bit: on Quora I&amp;rsquo;ve started a board called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Things-Everyone-Should-Know&quot;&gt;Things Everyone Should Know&lt;/a&gt;.  As described there, it is &amp;ldquo;Inspired by Seth Godin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2004/12/the_top_1000_th.html&quot;&gt;The top 1,000 things to know&lt;/a&gt; post.  I&amp;rsquo;d like to eventually turn these into a daily email newsletter or something.  Some of these tell you what you should know, others go into more depth and explain how.  This is a work in progress.&amp;rdquo;  The most exciting thing is that I&amp;rsquo;m often learning as I go along.  There&amp;rsquo;s so little I know, so much to know.  Gotta keep on moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posts to date consist of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Things-Everyone-Should-Know/Making-an-Omelette&quot;&gt;Making an Omelette&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Things-Everyone-Should-Know/Memorize-Personal-Information&quot;&gt;Memorize Personal Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Things-Everyone-Should-Know/Riding-a-Bike&quot;&gt;Riding a Bike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Things-Everyone-Should-Know/Driving-Safely&quot;&gt;Driving Safely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Things-Everyone-Should-Know/Doing-Laundry&quot;&gt;Doing Laundry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Things-Everyone-Should-Know/Keeping-a-Clean-House&quot;&gt;Keeping a Clean House&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Things-Everyone-Should-Know/Selective-Service-Requirements&quot;&gt;Selective Service Requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out.  I&amp;rsquo;d love suggestions for more topics to cover. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ctogden.com//2013/01/02/awhile/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ctogden.com//2013/01/02/awhile/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekly Dispatch, Week 5</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I missed another week (maybe I should call these bi-weekly dispatches from now on).  I blame the &lt;span title=&quot;Hurricane Sandy&quot;&gt;hurricane&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s new?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finished the first half of Gene Wolfe&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Book of the New Sun&lt;/em&gt; series, &lt;em&gt;Shadow &amp;amp; Claw&lt;/em&gt;.  It&amp;rsquo;s not bad, but it&amp;rsquo;s very strange.  At one point, the protagonist and his allies ate the corpse of the his first love&amp;hellip;  I&amp;rsquo;m also not sure how to classify it.  Is it science fiction or fantasy?  I guess both.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had some free time for once, and used it to write some letters to or call various friends and family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I weathered the hurricane with some friends.  Sleeping on a sofa half my size wasn&amp;rsquo;t too comfortable, but being with friends was enjoyable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 24 Hours of Good Hackathon hosted by Google was canceled.  That&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate, but it gives me time to get caught up on this homework that&amp;rsquo;s been piling up (despite delays of deadlines due to the storm).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ctogden.com//2012/11/02/weekly-dispatch-5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ctogden.com//2012/11/02/weekly-dispatch-5/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekly Dispatch, Week 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I missed a week.  Oops.  Since I send a weekly email to my sister summarizing the week, I still have a record of what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to.  But I&amp;rsquo;m not going to bother recapping it here.  I&amp;rsquo;ll stick with what&amp;rsquo;s fresh in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a week over-saturated with homework, to the point where some of it was never done or, in one case, never started.  Ouch!  But despite all that, this weekend was surprisingly free.  Few imminent deadlines, for once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that worked out very nicely, because my parents and my sister Heather were able to come down to Long Island for a visit.  We spent the day in beautiful Huntington and saw the movie &lt;em&gt;Looper&lt;/em&gt; before they dropped me off back at Stony Brook.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a bit of time to update my &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-writers-room/8d6e7df7ae58&quot;&gt;Sparks File&lt;/a&gt; and check some items off my reading list (I&amp;rsquo;ve been copying links to a text file when I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to read them immediately).  And on Quora I wondered, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/NetBeans/Is-there-a-way-to-check-for-undocumented-methods-in-Netbeans&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is there a way to check for undocumented methods in Netbeans?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;  I know it&amp;rsquo;s a good coding practice to document methods before writing any code, but sometimes one forgets&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve some postcards and emails I&amp;rsquo;d like to write, so that&amp;rsquo;s it for now.  Farewell.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ctogden.com//2012/10/21/weekly-dispatch-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ctogden.com//2012/10/21/weekly-dispatch-3/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekly Dispatch, Week 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had intended to start these weekly dispatches after writing &lt;a href=&quot;http://ctogden.com/post/working-on-it&quot;&gt;Working on It&lt;/a&gt;, but I came down with a cold that lasted two weeks and I was also very busy with assignments and exams.  So here&amp;rsquo;s some catch up, if I can remember anything.  (Also, I had intended this to be a progress report, but you&amp;rsquo;ll have to excuse my lack of progress for now.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been on Quora a lot recently, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t written many answers or asked many questions in a while.  I did post an answer today, though, to a question I myself posed a few months ago:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Life/What-are-things-every-young-adult-should-know/answer/Christopher-Ogden&quot;&gt;My answer to &amp;ldquo;What are things every young adult should know?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to have more answers to that question, and this one as well: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Economics/What-is-The-Fable-of-the-Bees&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is The Fable of the Bees?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading the first half of Gene Wolfe&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Book of the New Sun&lt;/em&gt;.  It&amp;rsquo;s brilliant, confusing, and disturbing, all at once.  As I posted to Facebook the other day, &amp;ldquo;Shadow &amp;amp; Claw has got to be one of the strangest books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. I&amp;rsquo;m about 300 pages in, and there&amp;rsquo;s so much going on. They just ate the corpse of the protagonist&amp;rsquo;s first love&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may finish the book tonight, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure there will be much resolution.  I do see myself ordering the second half from Amazon soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transitions.&lt;/em&gt;  Lamenting the gradual decay of dear friendships of old.  Happy to have made some new friends recently.  I am happy, but can&amp;rsquo;t help being sad.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Considering the future.&lt;/em&gt;  I know more and more what I want and what I don&amp;rsquo;t.  But how to get there?  Mostly work, hard work, and is there time?  I tell myself to relax.  And I have,  a little more than usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But how about now?&lt;/em&gt;  What can I do now, right now?  (Besides doing the work, that is.)  Most things worth having take a fair amount of effort to attain, but is there something I could attain now if only I realized what it was I&amp;rsquo;m after?  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m asking the wrong questions, and that&amp;rsquo;s why the answers are so befuddling.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited about the future of the Stony Brook Computing Society, our local student ACM chapter.  I&amp;rsquo;m serving as Vice President of the club this year, and we&amp;rsquo;ve seen a great resurgence in membership since I joined the club less than two years ago.  I remember meetings where there were only perhaps five other students present.  In fact, this was the norm at the time.  We recruited heavily at the start of this semester (our &amp;ldquo;Geek Games&amp;rdquo; puzzle hunt was a huge success) and we now have up to 60 members attending each of our general body meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At our meeting Friday, we brainstormed events and other ideas in preparation for our budget.  If we are able to do half of those things, this will be an amazing year.  And working with Hanne, Eric, and Phil (my fellow officers) I&amp;rsquo;m confident we can make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ctogden.com//2012/10/07/weekly-dispatch-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ctogden.com//2012/10/07/weekly-dispatch-1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Some things I believe in</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christian Minimalism[^1]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fallibilism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The serial comma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The importance of self-reflection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That I know nothing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intellectual property law reform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solving “Wicked Problems”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s not my job to change the world single-handedly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bless the Toolmakers[^2]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[^1]: “God is Love.” 1 John 4:8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;I like this line I found [here](http://www.winternet.com/~swezeyt/bible/cmin/cminMain.htm): “Everything else; doctrine, theology, tradition, ritual, must be secondary.”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[^2]: Refer to Robin Sloan’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://snarkmarket.com/2011/7320&quot;&gt;Bless the Toolmakers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;You should certainly read this post, but be aware that it does not offer a straightforward conclusion.  If you decide to skip it (shame on you), the gist of the article is that it’s okay to build tools that don’t scale, that software developers don’t need to build software that facilitates millions of transactions.  Because scale has its cost.  We may enable creation en masse, but then we are removed from the creative act.  What if those “people with toolmaking abilities spent their time and talent on artistic endeavors too”?

Louis-Jean Teitelbaum’s [response](http://ljt.meidosem.com/post/9795254025/bless-the-toolreaders), from which the previous quotation is taken, is also worth a read.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ctogden.com//2012/10/07/some-beliefs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ctogden.com//2012/10/07/some-beliefs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Working on It</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m half way through my degree, and despite my good grades I feel as if I&amp;rsquo;ve learned next to nothing.  I&amp;rsquo;m 20 (nearly 21) years old, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I know how to jumpstart a car or how to make sure I stay on the good side of the IRS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something has got to change.  Inspired by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.noexcuselist.com/&quot;&gt;No Excuse List&lt;/a&gt;, which I was reminded of by J.D. Bentley&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://jdbentley.com/institutionalized/&quot;&gt;Institutionalized&lt;/a&gt;, and Joel Gascoigne&amp;rsquo;s encouragement to &lt;a href=&quot;http://joel.is/post/22893893905/work-harder-on-yourself-than-you-do-on-your-startup&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Work harder on yourself than you do on your startup&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided it&amp;rsquo;s time for a &amp;ldquo;startup of the self&amp;rdquo;.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also decided to track my progress openly, as much as I am comfortable with, perhaps a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this involve?  I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure yet.  My goals are not written in stone.  But today I have plenty of options.  Online learning platforms are popping up left and right, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/&quot;&gt;edX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/&quot;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://venture-lab.org/&quot;&gt;Venture Lab&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mruniversity.com/&quot;&gt;Marginal Revolution University&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.udacity.com/&quot;&gt;Udacity&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/&quot;&gt;Team Treehouse&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/&quot;&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; (and the wider &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackexchange.com/sites&quot;&gt;Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;) provide a great way to get answers to nearly any question.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://lift.do/&quot;&gt;Lift&lt;/a&gt; encourages follow through on daily goals to help establish habits (see my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lift.do/users/1072867d6ae2ba25b107&quot;&gt;profile&lt;/a&gt;).  &lt;a href=&quot;http://duolingo.com/&quot;&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt; may be a great way to learn new languages, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://memrise.com/&quot;&gt;Memrise&lt;/a&gt; will help reinforce vocabulary through spaced repetition (it might also be worth looking into the courses from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fsi-language-courses.org/Content.php&quot;&gt;Foreign Service Institute&lt;/a&gt;.  Programming exercises are plentiful at &lt;a href=&quot;http://projecteuler.net/&quot;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackerrank.com/&quot;&gt;Hacker Rank&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.interviewstreet.com/&quot;&gt;Interviewstreet&lt;/a&gt;.  Many books and other resources are published online, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://eloquentjavascript.net/&quot;&gt;Eloquent JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://shapeofdesignbook.com/&quot;&gt;The Shape of Design&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://learn.shayhowe.com/html-css/&quot;&gt;A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to HTML &amp;amp; CSS&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go on, but it&amp;rsquo;s time to start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ctogden.com//2012/09/16/Working-On-It/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ctogden.com//2012/09/16/Working-On-It/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Irksome RSS Sponsorships</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier today, I tweeted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re going to include RSS feed sponsorships once a week, you should be blogging at least that often.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Christopher Ogden (@c_t_ogden) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/c_t_ogden/status/244444019357282305&quot; data-datetime=&quot;2012-09-08T14:36:10+00:00&quot;&gt;September 8, 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of my favorite blogs are now including advertisements amidst their other RSS items through services such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://syndicateads.net/&quot;&gt;The Syndicate&lt;/a&gt;.  I generally don&amp;rsquo;t have a problem with this.  If I&amp;rsquo;m not supporting their writing through a subscription I think it&amp;rsquo;s fine for them to earn money from serving ads.  But when the last four or five items in my Google Reader are advertisements, I do get annoyed.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, to be clear, I could easily unsubscribe.  And I might.  But I&amp;rsquo;d like to continue to follow these sites.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I have a simple solution?  Unfortunately, no.  It would be nice if these RSS ad networks only posted advertisements on weeks when other posts appeared.  But I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this is an option as advertisers are paying to be featured on these sites in advance, and the advertisements are often planned for a certain time for maximal effect.  And I am sure the bloggers don&amp;rsquo;t want to miss out on their share of the profits either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, then, what should I do?  What should we do?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ctogden.com//2012/09/08/irksome-rss-sponsorships/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ctogden.com//2012/09/08/irksome-rss-sponsorships/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resolutions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I revisited my New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolutions for 2012.  I was going to review them publicly here, but I think I&amp;rsquo;d rather simply state that progress was made for most items and while my follow through wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good as hoped for, I am proud of what I have achieved.  That said (and yes, I realize the year isn&amp;rsquo;t over yet), I&amp;rsquo;d like to set some new goals.  These will hopefully be more precise, measurable, and actionable.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to accomplish these goals by this date next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lose 20 pounds&lt;/strong&gt; - That&amp;rsquo;s about two pounds a month.  This might be the most difficult goal, but few things are more important than health and fitness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read 40 books&lt;/strong&gt; - I read a lot, but most of it is shorter pieces on the internet.  This isn&amp;rsquo;t healthy, sitting in front of a computer all day.  And I miss real books, I really do.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write 60 blog posts&lt;/strong&gt; - Someday I hope to receive a portion of my income from writing.  Also, putting things in writing is a great way to improve ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Launch an app&lt;/strong&gt; - I&amp;rsquo;m not sure of all the particulars yet, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to create some sort of small but meaningful application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things will appear to fill in the gaps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ctogden.com//2012/09/03/resolutions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ctogden.com//2012/09/03/resolutions/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>